

var quiz = { "JS" : [
	{
		"id" : 1,
		"question" : "Who introduced AWS ?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Bill Gates", 
			 "b":"Bernard Arnault", 
			 "c":"Jeff Bezos", 
			 "d":"Mark Zuckerberg"}
			],
		"answer":"Jeff Bezos",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 2,
		"question" : "What is AWS Fullform?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Amazon Web Security", 
			 "b":"Amazon Web Services", 
			 "c":"Amazon Web Software",
                   "d":"Amazon Web System"}
			],
		"answer":"Amazon Web Services",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 3,
		"question" : "In which year, AWS founded?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "1994", 
			 "b":"1999", 
			 "c":"2003",
                   "d":"2006"}
			],
		"answer":"2006",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 4,
		"question" : "Which of the following simply means to hardware or software load over web servers, that improver's the efficiency of the server as well as the application?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Load Balancing", 
			 "b":"Amazon Cloud-front", 
			 "c":"Elastic Load Balancer",
                   "d":"Security Management"}
			],
		"answer":"Load Balancing",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 5,
		"question" : "EC2 stands for ?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Elastic Compute Cloud", 
			 "b":"Elastic Cloud Compute",
			 "c":"Elastic Configuration Cloud",
			 "d":"Elastic Cloud Configuration"}
			],
		"answer":"Elastic Compute Cloud",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 6,
		"question" : "Amazon Web Services falls into which of the following cloud-computing category?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Software as a Service", 
			 "b":"Back-end as a Service",
			 "c":"Platform as a Service",
                   "d":"Infrastructure as a Service"}
			],
		"answer":"Infrastructure as a Service",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 7,
		"question" : "How many buckets can you create in AWS by default?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "25 buckets", 
			 "b":"50 buckets",
			 "c":"100 buckets",
                   "d":"200 buckets"}
			],
		"answer":"100 buckets",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 8,
		"question" : "Which of the following is a billing and account management service?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Amazon Mechanical Turk", 
			 "b":"Amazon DevPay",
			 "c":"Multi-Factor Authentication",
			 "d":" Amazon Elastic MapReduce",
			}
			],
		"answer":"Amazon DevPay",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 9,
		"question" : "What are the advantages of Auto Scaling?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Fault Tolerance", 
			 "b":"Better Availability",
			 "c":"Better Cost Management",
			 "d":"All of the above"
			}
			],
		"answer":"All of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 10,
		"question" : "Which of the following is an edge-storage or content delivery system that caches data in different physical locations?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Amazon CloudFront", 
			 "b":"Amazon SimpleDB",
			 "c":"Amazon Associate Web Services",
			 "d":"Amazon Relational Database Service"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Amazon CloudFront",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
{
		"id" : 11,
		"question" : "Azure VMs and storage services fall under which of the following cloud computing models?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "IaaS", 
			 "b":"PaaS", 
			 "c":"SaaS", 
			 "d":"All of the above"}
			],
		"answer":"IaaS",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 12,
		"question" : "Which Azure management tool analyzes resources and provides recommendations to optimize deployments?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Azure Advisor", 
			 "b":"Azure Recommend", 
			 "c":"Azure Proactive",
                   "d":"Azure Optimize"}
			],
		"answer":"Azure Advisor",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 13,
		"question" : "Which of the following Azure services helps enterprises deploy and manage a hybrid cloud architecture?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Azure Outposts", 
			 "b":"Azure Pack", 
			 "c":"Azure Stack",
                   "d":"Azure Hybrid"}
			],
		"answer":"Azure Stack",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 14,
		"question" : "Azure experienced a multiday outage in March 2020 that affected customers in Europe and the United Kingdom. Customers were unable to spin up VMs and suffered delays with Azure Pipeline. What caused the outage?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Human error", 
			 "b":"Capacity issues", 
			 "c":"Severe weather",
                   "d":"Security breach"}
			],
		"answer":"Capacity issues",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 15,
		"question" : "Azure Service Fabric is a distributed systems platform aimed primarily at:",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Containers and microservices", 
			 "b":"Serverless architectures",
			 "c":"Blockchain projects",
			 "d":"All of the above"}
			],
		"answer":"Containers and microservices",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 16,
		"question" : "Which Microsoft Azure cloud security tool can an enterprise use for key management?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Azure GuardDuty", 
			 "b":"Azure Lockdown",
			 "c":"Azure Key Management",
                   "d":"Azure Key Vault"}
			],
		"answer":"Azure Key Vault",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 17,
		"question" : "Microsoft Azure is the only cloud that offers a service-level agreement (SLA) for its API management service.",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "True", 
			 "b":"False"}
			],
		"answer":"False",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 18,
		"question" : "Azure Blob storage offers how many storage tiers?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "3", 
			 "b":"4",
			 "c":"5",
			 "d":"8",
			}
			],
		"answer":"4",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 19,
		"question" : "Which company did Microsoft acquire to help customers plan and execute migrations to Azure?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "CyberX", 
			 "b":"Cloudify",
			 "c":"Cloudyn",
			 "d":"Movere"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Movere",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 20,
		"question" : "Azure Cognitive Services is made up of which five service components?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Speech, Language, Search, Video and Translation", 
			 "b":"Vision, Speech, Language, Search and Decision",
			 "c":"Language, Translation, Vision, Knowledge and Audio",
			 "d":"Knowledge, Translation, Audio, Visual and Speech"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Vision, Speech, Language, Search and Decision",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
{
		"id" : 21,
		"question" : "When did Google cloud platform launch?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "2006", 
			 "b":"2005", 
			 "c":"2007", 
			 "d":"2008"}
			],
		"answer":"2008",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 22,
		"question" : "What do you mean by cloud computing? Select the best answer.",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "A term referring to storing data over the internet.", 
			 "b":"A platform where you can access huge amounts of data without having a hard disk.", 
			 "c":"A platform where you can access the data from a remote server.",
                   "d":"All of the above."}
			],
		"answer":"All of the above.",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 23,
		"question" : "Cloud computing offers how many service models?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "3", 
			 "b":"4", 
			 "c":"2",
                   "d":"5"}
			],
		"answer":"3",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 24,
		"question" : "Developing and deploying web-based software in data centers is managed by which Google cloud platform service?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Compute engine", 
			 "b":"Google App engine", 
			 "c":"Kubernetes Engines",
                   "d":"Security Management"}
			],
		"answer":"Google App engine",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 25,
		"question" : "Google App Engine follows which cloud computing model?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "IAAS", 
			 "b":"SAAS",
			 "c":"PAAS",
			 "d":"DAAS"}
			],
		"answer":"PAAS",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 26,
		"question" : "Google App Engine comes under which kind of service?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Compute service", 
			 "b":"Networking service",
			 "c":"Storage service",
                   "d":"Infrastructure  Service"}
			],
		"answer":"Compute service",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 27,
		"question" : "Which of the following languages are supported by the Google app engine?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Python", 
			 "b":"Java",
			 "c":"C++",
                   "d":"All of the above"}
			],
		"answer":"All of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 28,
		"question" : "Google app engine follows which type of architecture?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Layered architecture", 
			 "b":"Client-Server architecture.",
			 "c":"Event-Driven architecture.",
			 "d":"Microservices architecture.",
			}
			],
		"answer":"Microservices architecture.",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 29,
		"question" : "What are the advantages of Auto Scaling?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Fault Tolerance", 
			 "b":"Better Availability",
			 "c":"Better Cost Management",
			 "d":"All of the above"
			}
			],
		"answer":"All of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 30,
		"question" : "Google Compute Engine comes under which kind of service?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Compute service", 
			 "b":"Networking service",
			 "c":"Storage service",
			 "d":"Big data service"
			}
			],
		"answer":"Compute service",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
{
		"id" : 31,
		"question" : "Why is serverless computing associated with the NoOps concept?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Serverless computing eliminates servers of all types", 
			 "b":"Serverless computing requires operations teams to be involved as much as developers", 
			 "c":"Serverless computing removes server management obligations", 
			 "d":"Serverless computing is not associated with NoOps"}
			],
		"answer":"Serverless computing removes server management obligations",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 32,
		"question" : "What do you mean by cloud computing? Select the best answer.",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "A term referring to storing data over the internet.", 
			 "b":"A platform where you can access huge amounts of data without having a hard disk.", 
			 "c":"A platform where you can access the data from a remote server.",
                   "d":"All of the above."}
			],
		"answer":"All of the above.",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 33,
		"question" : "Cloud computing offers how many service models?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "3", 
			 "b":"4", 
			 "c":"2",
                   "d":"5"}
			],
		"answer":"3",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 34,
		"question" : "Which of these traits is a benefit of a serverless architecture?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Reduced cost because you only pay when your code runs", 
			 "b":"Improved scalability that enables you to serve extremely active traffic periods", 
			 "c":"Faster workflows for IT departments due to less worry about server obligations",
                   "d":"All of the above"}
			],
		"answer":"All of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 35,
		"question" : "What best describes the payment structure of most serverless cloud providers?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Pay per use", 
			 "b":"One-time flat service fee",
			 "c":"Multi-tiered monthly service subscription plans",
			 "d":"Fixed hourly rate"}
			],
		"answer":"Pay per use",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 36,
		"question" : "When does the serverless model provide the most economic benefit?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "When event loads are consistent", 
			 "b":"When event loads are inconsistent",
			 "c":"When the application is used internally and not externally",
                   "d":"It is not economically beneficial to use serverless"}
			],
		"answer":"When event loads are inconsistent",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 37,
		"question" : "Serverless is a good choice for an application in which of these cases?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "When the app's event processing is resource-intensive", 
			 "b":"When you have an app that is consistently bombarded with events",
			 "c":"When the app's event processing is not resource-intensive",
                   "d":"All of the above"}
			],
		"answer":"When the app's event processing is not resource-intensive",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 38,
		"question" : "Which of the following automation services is NOT a serverless platform provider?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "AWS Lambda", 
			 "b":"Client-Server architecture.",
			 "c":"Microsoft Azure Functions",
			 "d":"None of the above",
			}
			],
		"answer":"None of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 39,
		"question" : "What are the advantages of Auto Scaling?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Fault Tolerance", 
			 "b":"Better Availability",
			 "c":"Better Cost Management",
			 "d":"All of the above"
			}
			],
		"answer":"All of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	},
	{
		"id" : 40,
		"question" : "Which of the following is a good use case for serverless computing?",
		"options" : [
			{"a": "Microservices", 
			 "b":"Event processing",
			 "c":"NoOps applications",
			 "d":"All of the above"
			}
			],
		"answer":"All of the above",
		"score":0,
		"status": ""
	}
	

	
	]
}




var quizApp = function() {

	this.score = 0;		
	this.qno = 1;
	this.currentque = 0;
	var totalque = quiz.JS.length;

	
	this.displayQuiz = function(cque) {
		this.currentque = cque;
		if(this.currentque <  totalque) {
			$("#tque").html(totalque);
			$("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
			$("#next").attr("disabled", false);
			$("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
	
			
			$("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);	
			 $("#question-options").html("");
			for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
			  if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
		
				$("#question-options").append(
					"<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
					"<label class='form-check-label'>" +
							  "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option'   id='q"+key+"' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
								  quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
							 "</span></label>"
				);
			  }
			}
		}
		if(this.currentque <= 0) {
			$("#previous").attr("disabled", true);	
		}
		if(this.currentque >= totalque) {
				$('#next').attr('disabled', true);
				for(var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
					this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
				}
			return this.showResult(this.score);	
		}
	}
	
	this.showResult = function(scr) {
		$("#result").addClass('result');
		$("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr  + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
		for(var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
			var res;
			if(quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
					res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
			} else {
				res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
			}
			$("#result").append(
			'<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
			'<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
			'<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
			
			'</div>' 
			
			);
			
		}
	}
	
	this.checkAnswer = function(option) {
		var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
		option = option.replace(/\</g,"&lt;")   //for <
		option = option.replace(/\>/g,"&gt;")   //for >
		option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")

		if(option ==  quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
			if(quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
				quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
				quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
		}
		} else {
			quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
		}
		
	}	
	 
	this.changeQuestion = function(cque) {
			this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
			this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);	
			
	}
	
}


var jsq = new quizApp();

var selectedopt;
	$(document).ready(function() {
			jsq.displayQuiz(0);		
		
	$('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function(e) {

			//var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
			$(this).prop("checked", true);
				selectedopt = $(this).val();
		});
		
			
			 
	});

	
	
	
	$('#next').click(function(e) {
			e.preventDefault();
			if(selectedopt) {
				jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
			}
			jsq.changeQuestion(1);
	});	
	
	$('#previous').click(function(e) {
		e.preventDefault();
		if(selectedopt) {
			jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
		}
			jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
	});	



